Dr. Conor O'Driscoll

Department of Economic Geography, Faculty of Spatial Sciences, University of Groningen, The Netherlands ☑ c.odriscoll@rug.nl | У @conorodriscollx | ☎ Conor O'Driscoll

Personal Profile

Assistant Professor in The University of Groningen's Department of Economic Geography. Main fields of interest include Economic Geography, Regional Science, Urban Economics, and Transportation Science. Proficient in spatial analysis which employs advanced econometric techniques (STATA, QGIS, and R).

Education

PhD in Economics

October 2020 – August 2023

University College Cork, Ireland

Department of Economics

University College Cork, Ireland • Dissertation Title: Urban Sprawl: Land-Use, Travel Behaviours, and Emissions in Ireland.

Supervisors: Prof. Justin Doran, Dr. Frank Crowley, Dr. Nóirín McCarthy.

PhD Committee: Dr. Edward Lahiff (Independent Chair; University College Cork), Prof. Aisling Reynolds-Feighan (External Examiner; University College Dublin), Dr. John Eakins (Internal Examiner; University College Cork).

BA: Economics and History

September 2017 – September 2020

University College Cork

Cork, Ireland

• Grade: Upper Second-Class Honours (3.33-3.67 GPA) with a First-Class Honours (4.0 GPA) Minor Dissertation.

Employment

Assistant Professor in Economic Geography	October 2023 –
Department of Economic Geography	University of Groningen, The Netherlands
Senior Demonstrator in Economics	September 2022 – June 2023
Centre For Policy Studies	University College Cork, Ireland
Teaching Assistant in Economics	October 2020 – June 2023
Department of Economics	University College Cork, Ireland
Postgraduate Tutor in Business, Social Sciences, and P	Public Policy June 2021 – June 2023
Skills Centre	University College Cork, Ireland
Research Assistant	April 2021 – July 2022; July 2023 – September 2023

Teaching Experience

Department of Economics

Statistics

Data Collection, Analysis, and Interpretation; Quantitative Research Methods; Mathematics For Business; Research in Economics; Statistical and Econometric Methods.

Economics

Introductory Microeconomics; Microeconomic Reasoning and Decision Making; Economics and Business; Economics and Social Issues; Intermediate Microeconomics; Economics and Labour Markets; Introductory Macroeconomics; Macroeconomic Analysis; Economics and Social Issues; Money and Monetary Policy; Intermediate Macroeconomics; Economics and Welfare; Global Political Economy.

Research Supervision

PhD Proposals [5]; MSc Dissertations [10]; Undergraduate Dissertations/Projects [18].

Awards and Honors

Best Paper by an Early Career Researcher - Honourable Mention RSAI-BIS Early Career Colloquium Regional Science Association International: British and Irish Section November 2022 Postgraduate Researcher of The Year, 2021-2022 College of Business and Law College of Business and Law, University College Cork December 2023

January 1, 2024 1

Affiliations and Professional Service

Research Affiliations

Research Associate

Spatial and Regional Economic Research Centre

Research Associate

The Urban and Regional Studies Institute

August 2023 –
University College Cork, Ireland
October 2023 –
University of Groningen, The Netherlands

Editorial Positions

Chief Editor

The Boolean Journal

June 2021 – September 2023 University College Cork, Ireland

Referee Services

Journal of Geographical Systems, Urban Climate, The Boolean, The Spatial and Regional Economic Research Centre PhD Development Series.

Publications

Current Research Projects

Kevin Credit and Conor O'Driscoll. 2023. "Assessing Modal Tradeoffs and Associated Built Environment Characteristics Using a Cost-Distance Framework". *Under Review in the Journal of Transport Geography*. Conor O'Driscoll; Frank Crowley; Justin Doran; Nóirín McCarthy. 2023. "Land-Use Configurations and Population Distributions: A Case Study of UK and Irish Cities". *Under Review in Papers in Regional Science*. Conor O'Driscoll; Frank Crowley; Justin Doran; Nóirín McCarthy. 2023. "The School Run: Travel Behaviours and The Built Environment". *Under Review in Travel Behaviour and Society*.

Peer-Reviewed Journal Articles

Conor O'Driscoll; Frank Crowley; Justin Doran; Nóirín McCarthy. 2023. "Land-Use Mix in Ireland: Implications for Sustainable Development". *Journal of Maps*, 19(1), pp.1-7. doi: 10.1080/17445647.2023.2214165.

Conor O'Driscoll; Frank Crowley; Justin Doran; Nóirín McCarthy. 2023. "The relationships between socio-demographics, residential environments, travel considerations, and commute mode choice in Ireland". *Regional Studies*, pp.1-18. doi: 10.1080/00343404.2023.2199779.

Conor O'Driscoll; Frank Crowley; Justin Doran; Nóirín McCarthy. 2023. "Land-Use Mixing in Irish Cities: Implications for Sustainable Development". *Land Use Policy*, 128(5), pp.1-7. doi: 10.1016/j.landusepol.2023.106615. Conor O'Driscoll; Frank Crowley; Justin Doran; Nóirín McCarthy. 2022. "Retail Sprawl and CO2 Emissions: Retail Centres in Irish Cities". *Journal of Transport Geography*, 102(6), pp.1-12. doi: 10.1016/j.jtrangeo.2022.103376.

Industry and Policy Reports

Jane Bourke; Conor O'Driscoll; Josh O'Driscoll; Páidí O'Reilly. 2022. "Innovating in Ireland: Can We Fail Better?". *Cork University Business School.*

Selected Press Coverage

Conor O'Driscoll; Frank Crowley; Justin Doran; Nóirín McCarthy. 2023. "How the relationship between sociodemographics, residential environments and travel influence commuter choices". *Regional Studies Blog*.

Conor O'Driscoll. 2023. "Retail Centre Locations in Cork: The Case of Carrigtwohill". RTE Prime Time.

Conor O'Driscoll; Frank Crowley; Justin Doran; Nóirín McCarthy. 2022. "Planning For Sustainability: Future Retail Centre Locations". *The Boolean*, 6(8), pp.27-32. doi: 10.33178/boolean.2022.1.5.

Conor O'Driscoll; Frank Crowley; Justin Doran; Nóirín McCarthy. 2022. "The Links Between Where We Live and How We Commute". *RTE Brainstorm*.

Jane Bourke; Josh O'Driscoll; Conor O'Driscoll. 2022. "Does fear of failure hamper Irish business innovation?". *RTE Brainstorm*.

Conor O'Driscoll. 2021. "Why out of town retail parks don't make sense in a climate crisis". RTE Brainstorm.

Conor O'Driscoll. 2021. "Shopping Malls, GHG Emissions and The Role of Policymakers in "Green"

Transportation Infrastructure in Ireland". Regional Science Association International: Student Summer Series.

January 1, 2024 2

Main Conferences and Workshops

2023: Regional Science Association International: British and Irish Section; Cork University Business School Postgraduate Symposium.

2022: Regional Science Association International: British and Irish Section (Session Chair); Cork University Business School Postgraduate Symposium.

2021: Conference of Irish Geographers; Regional Science Association International: British and Irish Section (**Organising Committee Member**); Cork University Business School Postgraduate Symposium; UCC Spatial and Economic Research Centre Lunchtime Speaker Series; The North American Meetings of The Regional Science Association (**Session Chair**).

References

Professor Justin Doran: PhD Supervisor and Head of UCC's Department of Economics. Email: Justin.Doran@ucc.ie. Professor Edward Shinnick: Professor of Economics in UCC's Department of Economics. Email: E.Shinnick@ucc.ie. Dr. Jane Bourke: Senior Lecturer in UCC's Department of Economics. Email: Jane.Bourke@ucc.ie.

January 1, 2024 3